## **Armando Saavedra**

Data Scientist

### **Skills**

Machine Learning 4+ yrs

SQL 4+ yrs.

Data Visualization 2+ yrs.

Web development 1+ yrs.

Project Management 3+ yrs.

### **Education**

01/2018 - 12/2019

Information Science (M.Sc.)

University of Arizona

Data Science Machine Learning
Capstone Project: "Claim Assessment using Predictive Models".

01/2008 - 12/2012

#### **Economics (B.Sc.)**

Catholic University of Colombia

Econometrics • Finance
Bachelor's thesis: "Predicting price
in male cattle premiums using an
ARIMA model".

### **Contact**

- **Q** 8166 N Pocono Way, 85743 Tucson Arizona
- □ +01 520-403-8550
- dsaavedra1012@gmail.com
- github.com/armando

### **Biography**

Data Scientist and economist with experience designing and applying quantitative algorithms to predict or classify different sorts of information. The methods applied in my portfolio are: time series analysis, neural networks, knn clustering, multinomial logistic regression. I also have experience using Python, Rstudio and SQL.

## Work experience

#### **Advanced Research Analyst**

12/2019 - 12/2021

Strategic Research Office

Pima Community College, Tucson, AZ

#### **Detailed Achievements:**

- \* Machine learning implementation to predict academic behavior.
- \* Prepare reports about institutional performance.
- \* Facilitating Python training for office team.
- \* Spatial data analysis using GIS in R and Python.
- \* Dashboard implementation with Power BI and R.

#### **Junior Economist**

08/2011 - 01/2014

Office of Economic Research FEDEGAN, Bogota, Colombia

#### **Detailed Achievements:**

Use of time series analysis to predict monthly price in male cattle premiums. Where the follow methods were applied:

- \*Autoregressive Models -VAR
- \*AutoRegressive Integrated Moving Average -ARIMA

Structured a methodological framework for transferring production knowledge to different cattle associations.

#### **Financial Assistant**

05/2010 - 08/2011

Operations

BCSC, Bogota, Colombia

My responsibilities included:

- \* Teller operations
- \* Selling Financial Products
- \* Customer Service

### **Projects**

#### Training Intern Mentorship program

2021

2021

Strategic Research Office

Pima Community College

I created two classification programs and explained their real-life applications to a high school student I was mentoring.

# Training Machine Learning applications using Python

Strategic Research Office

Pima Community College

As part of my annual professional development, I

As part of my annual professional development, I created a training session about machine learning implementation focused on classification. To reach the goal, I applied two supervised ML models, a support vector machine, and Logistic Regression Model.